### **Emma Smith**

Location: Gloucester

Telephone: 07825241714

Email: <a href="mailto:smileandsparkle@hotmail.com">smileandsparkle@hotmail.com</a>

# Personal profile

After taking a career break to see my youngest daughter off to school - I'm now in a position to dive head first into a new world. During the pandemic I spent a lot of time dabbling with coding and web design/development, using free resources such as Team Treehouse, the Odin Project, Sololearn, Codecademy, Udemy and Free Code Camp. I would love to be given the opportunity to thrive into this industry - I can offer attention to detail, problem solving skills and high level social skills, all of which can be evidenced in my previous job roles and also in my home life. I absolutely thrive under pressure, and I'm not afraid to get my hands dirty. I'm flexible, happy to work from home or in the office and I can assure you that I would be an asset to any team.

## Education

- NCFE Cache level 2 Certificate in Understanding Children and Young People's Mental Health (2021)
- Certificate in Mortgage Advice and Practice (2013)
- A level Mathematics grade A (2007)
- National Certificate in Media Production (2006)
- 9 GCSEs grade A\*-C (2004)

# Work history

#### Mortgage Advisor, Lloyds Bank - October 2013 - Aug 2017

Employed originally as a Mortgage Advisor, I took on various roles and responsibilities during my time here. I was part of the team of advisors that saw the bank through new rules and regulations put in place by the Financial Conduct Authority on how mortgage advice should be given. I was then hand picked to sit on a Quality Assurance panel overseeing the work completed by our team, making sure it was up to standards so my attention to detail is second to none. Following this, my team was selected to work on a new project which involved us teaching ourselves new systems and databases and creating flowcharts, then teaching other teams how to interpret the data.

#### Buyer, Anixter Fasteners (now Optimas) - June 2008 - October 2013

As part of my role here, I was responsible for sourcing and purchasing important fixings such as nuts, bolts and washers for several high end companies such as McLaren, CAT and Stannah. During my time here I attended courses in negotiation training, time management

and leadership. It was a very fast paced role that required a specific skill set as I would very often be liaising with suppliers in China or America to source niche parts and arranging express freight with transport companies, in order to prevent the manufacturing process from coming to a stop in my clients factories.

Advance Administrator, Chelsea Building Society - September 2007 - June 2008
This was my first foray into the business world, after leaving education and a part time job at a supermarket. My responsibility was to process applications for customers wanting to borrow more money on top of their mortgage. I would be inputting data, taking phone calls, filing paperwork, liaising with other departments, contacting employers and looking into the original deeds of houses, in order to determine whether an additional loan would be feasible.

### Hobbies and interests

Outside of raising my 3 children I have to admit to being a bit of a nerd! I enjoy playing complex modern board games, I am part of a local board gaming group that meet up semi-regularly, building Lego, playing video games, and I've taken to a fascination with coding and web design, which I am hoping to build a career out of. I have basic skills in HTML, CSS, Python and Javascript, which I am building on daily using many different online resources and apps. I also enjoy proofreading and playtesting, which I do voluntarily for many board game designers to help with their rulebooks and beta versions of games.

References available on request